

Contact Details

Pablo Ibieta
CPF 236.705.918-40

Mibieta.pablo@gmail.com
pibieta@if.usp.br

☐ (+55) 11 959 360 119

Work Address

Rua do Matão Travessa R Nr. 187, Off. 331 CEP 05508-090 São Paulo, Brazil.

Personal Address

Rua Frei Inácio da Conceição 237, Apto 6 CEP 05362-040 São Paulo, Brazil.

Details and Publications

Curriculo Lattes
https://bit.ly/2CXGU8i
in/pibieta

7/pibieta

Languages

Spanish: Mother tongue

English: Fluent Portuguese: Fluent

French: Basic

Pablo Ibieta

Physicist / Data Scientist

About me Since 2012, I have worked as a scientific researcher in the area of Mathematical Physics. During this period, I have acquired advanced mathematical knowledge and learned several computational skills concerning data analysis. This involves the manipulation and interpretation of data, the use of statistical tools to compare data to models and the computation of experimental predictions using simulations. In order to complement these skills, basically oriented to industry applications, currently I am focused on the study and development of Python based Data Science and Machine Learning tools.

Experience

Sep 2012 - present

Junior Researcher and Teaching Assistant, Instituto de Física, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil. Project: *Topological Quantum Field Theories and Topological Phases of Matter* (5 PUBS).

Jan 2018

Visiting Professor, Universidad Mayor de San Andrés, Physics Department. La Paz, Bolivia. Project: *Taught the Group Theory and Physics course at the Summer School*

Sep 2005 - Feb 2010

Junior Researcher and Teaching Assistant. Institute for Theoretical Physics, Universidad Mayor de San Andrés, Physics Department. La Paz, Bolivia. Project: *Performed research on Loop Quantum Gravity* (1 PUB).

Education

2015 - 2019

Ph. D. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP).

São Paulo, Brazil. Thesis: Topological entanglement entropy and Area Law in Higher Gauge Theories.

2012 - 2015

M. Sc. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP)

São Paulo, Brazil. Thesis: Gauge and Matter Fields on the Lattice

2004 - 2010

Bachelor in Physics, Universidad Mayor de San Andrés (UMSA). La Paz, Bolivia. *Entropy of a Rotating Black Hole in LQG*.

Skills

Team Work

Teacher and coordinator of three undergraduate physics courses at USP. Teaching assistant of several courses at UMSA and USP.

Software Development

Senior experience using Python, R, C, C++, Mathematica, and SQL. Familiar with libraries Tensorflow, Keras, sklearn and XGBoost.

